<resources>

    <string name="app_name">BSA Ranks</string>

    <string name="scout">Scout</string>

    <string name="tenderfoot">Tenderfoot</string>

    <string name="secondclass">Second Class</string>

    <string name="firstclass">First Class</string>

    <string name="starscout">Star Scout</string>

    <string name="lifescout">Life Scout</string>

    <string name="eaglescout">Eagle Scout</string>

    <string name="default_desc">This app will introduce you to the seven ranks of the Boy Scouts of
        America. Click on a badge in the scrollable list above to learn about that rank.
    </string>

    <string name="scout_desc">Scout is the first rank. The badge is awarded when the boy
        demonstrates a rudimentary knowledge of the Scouting ideals such as tying a square knot and
        knowing the Scout oath, law, motto, and slogan.
    </string>

    <string name="tenderfoot_desc">Tenderfoot is the second rank. A Scout can work on the
        requirements for the Tenderfoot, Second Class, and First Class ranks at the same time, but
        each rank must be earned in sequence. The badge is awarded when the Scout completes
        requirements in the areas of Scoutcraft, physical fitness, citizenship, personal growth and
        Scout Spirit.
    </string>

    <string name="secondclass_desc">Second Class is the rank above Tenderfoot and below First Class.
        A Scout can work on the requirements for the Tenderfoot, Second Class, and First Class ranks
        at the same time, but must be earned in sequence. The badge is awarded when the Scout
        completes requirements in the areas of Scoutcraft, physical fitness, citizenship, personal
        growth and Scout Spirit.
    </string>

    <string name="firstclass_desc">First Class is the rank above Second Class and below Star Scout.
        A Scout can work on the requirements for the Tenderfoot, Second Class, and First Class ranks
        at the same time, but must earn them in sequence. The badge is awarded when the Scout
        completes requirements in the areas of Scoutcraft, physical fitness, citizenship, personal
        growth and Scout Spirit. At this point, Scouts stop practicing the Scout skills, and start
        working on leadership.
        \n\n
        The number of Scouts achieving First Class within one year of joining is still one of the
        key measures of unit effectiveness. Studies purportedly have shown that if a Scout achieves
        First Class within a year of joining, he typically stays in the Scout program for at least
        three years. Scouts who do so are purportedly more likely to retain Scout values as an adult
        and achieve the BSA primary mission of "producing useful citizens".
    </string>

    <string name="star_desc">Star is the rank above First Class and below Life Scout. It is the
        third-highest rank. Star is awarded when the Scout serves actively in the troop in a
        position of responsibility for at least 4 months; performs at least six hours of community
        service; and earns six merit badges (four of which must be required for Eagle Scout rank).
        \n\n
        Initially, the Life badge was awarded for five merit badges and the Star badge was awarded
        for ten. The order was reversed in the 1920s when it was decided that the five-pointed star
        of Star Scout better represented the five merit badges required for first rank above First
        Class. That symbolism disappeared when the number of merit badges required for Star was
        increased to six in 1990.
    </string>

    <string name="life_desc">Life is second-highest rank attainable and ranks above Star Scout and
        below Eagle. Life is awarded when the Scout serves actively in the troop, team or crew,
        serves in a position of responsibility for six months, and performs six hours of community
        service. Another thing a Scout must do in order to achieve Life is earn an additional five
        merit badges (three of which are required for the rank of Eagle), to make a minimum total of
        eleven merit badges (including the six previously required for Star). Finally, the Scout
        must pass a Scoutmaster conference, and board of review.
        \n\n
        Life was originally lower than Star, and originally required earning five specific merit
        badges concerned with health and fitness (First Aid, Lifesaving, Public Health, Personal
        Health and Athletics). It was changed in the 1920s when it was decided that the five-pointed
        star better represented the five merit badges required for Star, and the two were switched.
        Life\'s heart came to symbolize achievement in health and fitness, as the First Aid merit
        badge was required for both Life and Eagle for many years.
    </string>

    <string name="eagle_desc">Eagle Scout is the highest rank attainable in the Boy Scouting
        division. Since its introduction in 1911, the Eagle Scout rank has been earned by more than
        2 million young men.
        \n\n
        Requirements include earning a number of merit badges and demonstration of Scout Spirit,
        service and leadership. This includes an extensive service project that the Scout plans,
        organizes, leads, and manages. Eagle Scouts are presented with a medal and a badge that
        visibly recognizes the accomplishments of the Scout. Additional recognition can be earned
        through Eagle Palms, awarded for completing additional tenure, leadership and merit badge
        requirements.
    </string>

</resources>
